<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<CFile xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <variables>
    <variable name="current_count" type="INT"/>
  </variables>
  <sketch>
    <xhtml:p><![CDATA[


// This is the Arduino side of the project. The functions sketch_setup() and
// sketch_loop() provide the same functionality of the setup() and loop()
// functions of a regular Arduino sketch. On top of this code editor there is a
// variable table. You can add variables there that are shared between the 
// arduino code and the PLC code. Since they are shared, you can, for example,
// read a sensor on the arduino sketch and use the reading in a PLC program. 
// On the PLC side you must declare the same variable with the class "external"
// before being able to use it in your program.

// This Arduino sketch implementation is compatible with virtually every library
// or code you can possibly run on the regular Arduino IDE. You can create your
// own functions and also #include external libraries (as long as they are also
// installed on your Arduino IDE). The only catch is that your sketch_loop() 
// function cannot block (long while loop or delays), or else your PLC code will
// block as well.

// Notes about this particular demo: This code was taken from the Seven Segment
// demo on Wokwi at: https://wokwi.com/projects/385425800021357569.
// The value displayed in the 7 segment display is taken from the 
// 'current_count' variable which is shared with the main PLC program.
// You can run this code on the Wokwi simulation by selecting "compile only"
// on the upload dialog. At the end of the compilation, a message will appear
// showing the location of the compiled file. You can then upload this file
// to the Wokwi simulation by pressing F1 and selecting "Upload Firmware and
// Start Simulation..."

// Define the pins for each segment (a to g) and the common cathode pin

const int segmentPins[8] = {2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8};
const int commonCathodePin = 9;

// 7-segment display layout
//       A
//      ---
//  F |  G  | B
//      ---
//  E |     | C
//      ---
//       D

// Define the numbers to display on the seven-segment display
const byte numbers[11] = {
    B11111100, // 0
    B01100000, // 1
    B11011010, // 2
    B11110010, // 3
    B01100110, // 4
    B10110110, // 5
    B10111110, // 6
    B11100000, // 7
    B11111110, // 8
    B11110110  // 9
};

// Function to display a digit on the seven-segment display
void displayNumber(int num) 
{
    // Turn off all segments
    for (int i = 0; i < 8; i++) 
    {
        digitalWrite(segmentPins[i], LOW);
    }

    // Activate segments based on the number to be displayed
    for (int i = 0; i < 8; i++) 
    {
        if (bitRead(numbers[num], i) == HIGH) 
        {
            digitalWrite(segmentPins[7-i], HIGH);
        }
    }
}

void sketch_setup()
{
    // Set segment pins as outputs
    for (int i = 0; i < 7; i++) 
    {
        pinMode(segmentPins[i], OUTPUT);
    }

    // Set common cathode pin as output
    pinMode(commonCathodePin, OUTPUT);
}

void sketch_loop()
{
    displayNumber(current_count);
}
]]></xhtml:p>
  </sketch>
</CFile>
