<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<CFile xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <variables>
    <variable name="SerialMSG" type="STRING"/>
    <variable name="PrintMSG" type="BOOL"/>
  </variables>
  <sketch>
    <xhtml:p><![CDATA[


// This is the Arduino side of the project. The functions sketch_setup() and
// sketch_loop() provide the same functionality of the setup() and loop()
// functions of a regular Arduino sketch. On top of this code editor there is a
// variable table. You can add variables there that are shared between the 
// arduino code and the PLC code. Since they are shared, you can, for example,
// read a sensor on the arduino sketch and use the reading in a PLC program. 
// On the PLC side you must declare the same variable with the class "external"
// before being able to use it in your program.

// This Arduino sketch implementation is compatible with virtually every library
// or code you can possibly run on the regular Arduino IDE. You can create your
// own functions and also #include external libraries (as long as they are also
// installed on your Arduino IDE). The only catch is that your sketch_loop() 
// function cannot block (long while loop or delays), or else your PLC code will
// block as well.

// Notes about this particular demo: Since this demo uses the serial port, you
// cannot enable Modbus Serial on your project, otherwise it will conflict with
// the messages being printed from this sketch. Also, this sketch shares a
// STRING with the PLC side. This is not a regular c-string, it is an IEC 61131
// STRING. Variables shared between the PLC and Arduino sketch are always IEC
// 61131 variables. For normal datatypes like INT, REAL, DINT, etc, there are
// direct equivalents in C (int16_t, float and int32_t respectively), so you
// shouldn't have any problems with those. An IEC STRING however is a more 
// complex structure. You can typecast an IEC STRING into a c-string by using 
// (char *)STRING.body as shown in the example below.

void sketch_setup()
{
    Serial.begin(115200);
    Serial.println("Hello World! I'm starting now...");
}

void sketch_loop()
{
    if (PrintMSG)
    {
        Serial.println((char *)SerialMSG.body);
    }
}
]]></xhtml:p>
  </sketch>
</CFile>
